Srujana Burri +91 8143506279

Srujanareddyb94@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Having 6+ years of IT experience & working as Cloud DevOps Engineer on AWS cloud platform in Infrastructure provisioning, Migration & Administration related activities.

Skills Profile

Technical

Environment	AWS, Hadoop Support, Azure
DevOps tool	Jenkins, Maven, Docker
Artifactory	Nexus Repository
Version Control	Git, Bitbucket
Languages	Terraform
Database	MySQL
Ticketing Tools	JIRA, Service-Now, HPSM, SDP
Operating System	Redhat Linux, Windows

Functional

Management and Leadership Skills	Ability to produce realistic software schedules, Project Management, Strategic/ Tactical Planning, Business Analysis and Development, Budgeting/Forecasting, New product Development
Training & Development	Technical ability to Train and Troubleshoot

Professional Experience

Barclay- Capgemini Technology, Hyderabad

Nov 2022- Present

USCB Impairments - Cloud Engineer

- Worked on Cloud formation code to provision an Infrastructure for Prod environment.
- Good Knowledge in Cloud formation templates provisioning using AWS service catalog.
- Provisioned EMR, RDS, Ec2, S3 using the service catalog.
- Used AWS Anthena for querying.

Environment: AWS, Cloud Formation, servicecatalog, JIRA

Dec 2021- Sep30 2022

AVIVA - Cloud Migration Project - Capgemini Technology, Hyderabad

Cloud & DevOps Engineer

- Worked on Terraform code to provision an Infrastructure for Dev, UAT & SIT environments.
- Using Ansible and Packer script to build an AMI and configured them with encryption.
- Experienced in configuring Auto scaling, Load balancer to handle load on EMR services.
- Used Jenkins pipeline to deploy the source code from Bit Bucket to the live environment.
- Experienced in configuring Highly available, secure, robust VPC in AWS, configured security groups, Network access control list (NACL) & Routing tables.
- Created RDS database & S3 proxy setup for EMR clusters using terraform.
- Created runbook documents for Data pipeline.

Environment: AWS, Jenkins, Terraform, Packer, Ansible, JIRA

July 2020- Sep 2021

AWS DevOps Support Project -DXC Technology, Hyderabad

DevOps Support Engineer

- Configured AWS Identity Access Management (IAM) Group and users for improved login authentication.
- Proficient in various AWS Services like EC2, VPC, S3, IAM, SNS, Cloud Watch, EBS, Elastic Load Balancer, Auto Scaling, RDS, AWS CLI, Cloud Formation, Cloud watch, Elastic Beanstalk, Route53.
- Proficient in vulnerability management in AWS instances on Linux, Mac & Windows OS.
- Experienced in S3 Versioning and lifecycle policies to and backup files and archive files in Glacier.
- Created monitors, alarm, and notifications for EC2 hosts using Cloud Watch.
- Provided L2 and partial L3 support to application customers and provided troubleshooting to monitor triggered Incidents and quick solving of Issues.
- Deployed and configured Network load balancers.
- Responsible for monitoring overall network infrastructure and configuring high availability to avoid single point of failure.

Environment: AWS, Linux, ServiceNow, ServiceDeskPlus, Cloudwatch and Logic monitor

Analytics Platform Support- DXC Technology, Chennai

July 2017-Sep 2021

Hadoop Support

- Extensively used Cloudera Hadoop Distribution
- Good Knowledge in maintenance of Hadoop and Client / server database.
- Good hands-on experience in Linux OS platform and troubleshooting.
- Monitoring Hadoop cluster connectivity & security, and review Hadoop log files. Effectively monitoring the Hadoop jobs fixing
 the issues in case of job failures or delays. Monitoring is done on LM and production Server.
- Reducing the space on the disk by gzip and archiving the log files.
- Troubleshooting issues on possible ways and maintaining all services up & running fine. Restarting the services Knox, Hive, LLAP, Hue etc.
- DBA Responsibilities like design & implementation, software installation, configuration, database backup and recovery, database connectivity and security.
- Involved in Vulnerability management in Hadoop environment on both windows and Linux based vulnerabilities.
- Uploading the smart sense bundles.
- Configured Logic monitor monitoring tool for monitoring overall Hadoop services and maintains high-availability of the cluster.
- Proficient in Linux OS commands.

Environment: Hadoop, Linux, ServiceNow, LogicMonitor

Summary of Projects

Barclay UK Nov 2022-Sep 2023

Cloud Engineer

Migration of Hadoop services from on-premises to AWS cloud in EMR cluster, using the cloud formation templates with the service catalog application

AVIVA Canada Dec 2021-Sep 2022

Cloud & DevOps Engineer

Migration of Hadoop services & Informatica applications from on-premises to AWS cloud in EMR cluster, Environment provisioning and Migration has been automated using Terraform code and deployed it through Jenkins pipeline.

HMSA July 2020- Sep 2021

Cloud Administrator

Provisioning of Informatica High availability clusters in AWS cloud environment and monthly Operating system based Vulnerability management using SSM, Patch Manager.

DXC-Analytics Platform Support

July 2017-Sep 2021

Big-data & Linux Support

Monitoring Hadoop cluster connectivity & security, and review Hadoop log file. DBA Responsibilities like design & implementation, software installation, configuration, database backup and recovery, database connectivity and security.

Training and Seminars

Completed AWS Solution architect course in Udemy.

Completed Linux administration trainings provided by Red-hat Enterprises.

Certifications

AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate (SAA-C02)

CID: AWS01228770

Score: 775

AWS Certified Cloud practitioner

Education

B. TECH in Electronics & Communication Engineering (2012-2016) at Vignan Institute of Technology and Sciences, Hyderabad.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true and correct.

Date:

Place: Hyderabad

Signature (Srujana)